- 弄了包烟 蓝电牌的 - 别臭美了
- Pack of smokes and Brown Thunder.- Don't get cocky, boy.
谢谢你
Thank you.
还有冷饮
Cold drinks?
冷冻机开一天了
Been running the freezers all day.
要我说 发电机可不是做这个的
Not the most practical use of the generators to my mind.
但也很神奇啊
It's kind of amazing.
总督觉得值就值
The Governor feels it's worth it.
为了很棒的派对干杯
Well, to a great party.
能给我透露一点今晚的好戏吗
Now, if you would just drop me a hint about tonight.
没有词语能完美地描述出
Hmm. Mere words cannot adequatly describe.
即将到来的庆典
the festivities ahead.
佩妮 别这样
Penny. Penny, no.
放松 佩妮 我们走
Easy, easy. Penny, let's go.
现在是午睡时间
It's nap time now.
午睡时间
Nap time.
佩妮 别这样
Penny, no.
佩妮
Penny. Hey, hey, hey.
别动 别动
Come on. Come on.
放轻松
Take it easy.
没事的
It's all right.
有我在
Hey, I'm here.
爸爸还爱着你
Daddy still loves you.
你知道的 对吧
You know that, right?
没事了
All right. All right.
来 对
Come on. Yeah.
佩妮
Hey, Penny.
《行尸走肉》
瑞克
Rick,
你还清醒吗
you with me?
瑞克
Rick?
- 让我看看婴儿 - 我们得给孩子喂点吃的
- Let me see the baby. - Well, we gotta feed it.
我们有婴儿能吃的东西吗
We got anything baby can eat?
好消息是她看起来很健康
The good news is she looks healthy.
但是她需要婴儿食物
But she needs formula.
不然她活不了多久
And soon she won't survive.
不 我不会让她死的
No, no way… Not her.
我们不能再失去任何人了 我出去一趟
We ain't losing nobody else. I'm going for a run.
- 我掩护你 - 我也去
- I'll back you up. - I'll go too.
好的 想想我们去哪儿 贝丝
OK, think where we're going. Beth.
他刚刚失去他的妈妈
The kid just lost his mom.
- 他爸也不太正常 - 我会照看他的
- His dad ain't doing so hot. - I'll look out for him.
你们俩去围栏那儿 太多行尸聚集
You two get to the fence.Too many will pile up.
我们就麻烦了
We got ourselves a problem.
格伦 玛姬 我们走
Glenn, Maggie, Vámonos.
瑞克
Rick!
去大门那里
Get to the gate.
快点 天快黑了
Come on, we're gonna lose the light.
85街有个小杂货店
There's a Piggly Wiggly on 85.
不能去 婴儿区已经没东西了
No, baby section's been cleared.
洛莉让我多留心婴儿食品 但我一直没找到
Lori asked me to keep an eye out. I haven't had much luck.
还有没被完全洗劫的地方吗
Is there any place that hasn't been completely looted?
我们在北边看到了购物中心的标志
We saw signs for a shopping center just north of here.
嗯 但是街上残骸太多车开不过去
Yeah, but there's too much debris on the road to a car to get through there.
我能带你们一个人去
I can take one of you.
我跟你去
I'll go.
不行 玛姬
No, Maggie,
你经历了太多 还是我去吧
after everything that you've been through, okay, I'll go.
我想去 为了洛莉 我必须去
I want to go. For Lori, I have to.
好吧
Ok.
我爱你 注意安全
I love you. Be safe.
我会的
I will.
好了
All right!
最开始我们只有九个人
First time we gathered, there was nine of us.
躲在一间公寓 只有猪肉罐头和咸饼干
holed up in an apartment with Spam and saltine crackers.
看看我们现在
Well, look at us now.
我们建造了一个可以称之为家的地方
We've built a place we can call home.
或许是由布基胶带和绳子捆绑而成的
Maybe held together with duct tape and string,
但是成功了
but it works.
这是我们的 我引以为傲
It's ours. I'll take it.
所以今天
So today.
我们庆祝这来之不易的成就
we celebrate how far we've come.
缅怀我们失去的同伴
We remember those we've lost.
为我们自己举杯
We raise a glass… to us.
（小镇建设改善计划）
（佩妮）
再等一段时间比较好
Suggesting we delay a couple of days.
等不及 已经万事俱备了
We can't wait. Everything's ready.
我和莫尔一样喜欢派对
I love a party as much as the next fellow.
相信我 我喜欢派对
Trust me, I love a party.
- 但是我们会消耗很多资源 - 是的
- But we're using a lot of resources. - Yeah.
比如发电机
For instance, the generators.
我以为你喜欢派对呢
I thought you love a party.
行了 小米 求你轻松点吧
Come on, Milty, lighten up, for Christ's sake.
放松一下 好好玩玩
Let your hair down, man. Have some fun for once.
- 我喜欢玩 - 那就没问题了
- I like fun. - Then there's no problem.
恕我无礼
If I might.
我这周一直在做实验
You know, I've been working on an experiment all week.
让电力达到我需要的水平不容易
It's been a challenge getting the level of power I need.
- 而今晚的派对耗电很大 - 你想要什么
- And with everything going on tonight… - What are you asking?
推迟今晚的派对
Postpone tonight.
不行
No way.
等会 让他说完
Hang on. Let's hear him out.
- 你需要多久 - 不需要太长时间
- How long do you need? - I don't need long.
- 多久 - 十天
- How long? - 10 days.
- 不行 - 六天
- No. - Six?
- 不行 - 那么
- No. - How about…
今晚你好好放松一下
How about you enjoy yourself tonight.
明早接着实验 怎么样
and then begin the experiment over in the morning, huh?
好吧 可以
Uh, yeah. That could work.
你很乐在其中是吗
You get off on that?
在别人的地方随便乱闯
Poking around other people's things?
我们没隐瞒什么事情
We got nothing to hide here.
没隐瞒事情的人 通常不会自卖自夸
People who had noting to hide don't usually feel the need to say so.
有道理
That's fair.
我们都有自己的秘密
We all have our secrets, huh?
比如佩妮
Like Penny?
你知道佩妮的事
You know about Penny?
那你应该知道我很爱她
Then you know I loved her.
我敢说你对所有女人都这么说
Bet you say that about all the girls.
你误会我了
You got the wrong idea about me.
我不过是一个希望为我在乎的人
I'm just a guy trying to do right.
做对的事情的人
by the people I care about.
你想离开 安德莉亚想留下
Now, you want to leave, Andrea wants to stay.
所以你想逼我做出选择
So you want me to take choice out of the equation.
想逼我把你赶出去
You want me to kick you out.
其实我本打算把刀还你
Actually, I was about to give your sword back.
以为你会喜欢这里
Guess you fit in.
我们相处得本来很愉快
We've enjoyed having you.
对我来说 这真的很棘手
This is a real problem for me.
大家遵守规则 不管规则是真是假
People follow the rules. And whether or not it's true,
他们都相信这样能够保他们活命
they believe it's what keeps them alive.
你违反了规则
You turned that upside down.
破坏了规矩
You've broken the rules.
如果我不闻不问 就会造成混乱
And if I don't do anything, I invite anarchy.
这样怎么样
How about this?
我不把你今天的失态告诉大家
I keep a lid on your little outburst,
但你要加入科研小队
you join the research team.
你有一身技能 而且不怕行尸
You obviously have skills and you're not afraid of biters.
莫尔会照顾你和
Merle will take care of you and…
怎么样
How'd it go?
她很有个性
She's all personality, that one.
对我们有麻烦吗
Do we have a problem?
没有
No. No.
叫安德莉亚过来见我
Send Andrea over to me.
你带科研小队去填补一下库存
You can take the research team to get more grist for the mill.
我会处理好这事的
I can handle this.
好的
All right.
周围怎么样了
How's the perimeter look?
行尸都散开了
We've got the walkers spread out.
需要帮忙吗
Need help?
你的朋友们 他们都是好人
Your friends, they… they were good folks.
他们是我家人
They were family.
我一辈子就只有一个这样的朋友
I think I had one friend like that my whole life.
你却有一群
You got a whole group.
我对他们的死很遗憾
Sorry you lost them.
再挖两个坑
I need two more.
- 瑞克呢 - 还在里面
- Rick? - Still inside.
我等会去找他
Okay, I'll get him.
一天之内我们失去了三分之一的人
A third of our group in one day.
就因为一个混蛋
'Cause of one asshole.
有时我觉得一开始把犯人杀光就好了
Part of me wishes that we killed all the prisoners on sight.
阿克塞尔和奥斯卡看起来像是好人
Axel and Oscar seem like good guys.
撤离刚开始的时候
When the evacuations started,
T仔开着教堂的车去他认识的每个老人家里
T-Dog drove his church van to the home of every senior he knew.
看他们需不需要帮助
just in case they needed a ride.
他救了我很多次
He saved my ass a thousand times.
他不只是好人 他是最好的人
He wasn't just a good guy, he was the best.
他是关门时被咬的
Got bit closing the gate.
如果他不关门的话
If he hadn't done that…
遭殃的有可能是玛姬
It could have been Maggie.
我知道这不对 但是
It's wrong, but…
我随时都愿意用别人的性命换我们人的性命
I will trade any number of people for one of us any day.
怎么了 莫尔说事情很紧急
What's wrong? Merle said it was urgent.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
- 是米琼恩 - 她怎么了
- It's Michonne. - What about her?
她不请自入 偷走了武器
She broke in, stole her weapon.
拿走自己的东西可不算偷
She can't steal something that's hers.
然后她又闯进了私人领地
Then she went into a private place.
屠杀了半打关押的行尸
and slaughtered half a dozen captive biters.
你为什么要关押行尸
Why would you have captive biters?
我自有道理 但现在不想纠缠这个问题
There's a good reason I don't want go in through right now.
好吧
Okay.
关键是 我想跟她好好谈一谈
Point is, I tried to talk to her about it.
结果她用剑指着我
and she pulled her sword on me.
就指在我脖子上
Held it to my throat.
不敢相信你也会感到惊讶
Can't imagine that surprises you.
除非她受到威胁 否则决不会那么做
She wouldn't do that unless she felt threatened.
她让大家感到很不自在
She makes people uncomfortable.
有人想要她离开 但我不想这么做
Some people want her to leave and I don't want that.
外面的情况正变得越来越糟
It's ugly out there and it's getting rse every day.
可是她逼得我别无选择
But she put my back against the wall here.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
我意思是外面那一套在这里行不通
I'm saying what works out there doesn't work in here.
我们可不是什么野蛮人
You know, we're not barbarians.
- 我们得谈谈 - 我们得离开
- We got to talk. - We got to go.
总督刚刚告诉了我发生了什么事
The Governor told me what happened.
米琼恩 你必须要收敛一点
Michonne, you can't do things like this.
你会吓着别人的
You freaking people out.
你都吓着我了
You freaking me out.
负责东北边防御的是几个女孩
The northeast wall is guarded by some girl.
我们可以在天黑后溜出去
We can escape there after dark.
我们在这里不是囚犯
We are not prisoners here.
这里的人只有进 没有出
No one who comes here leaves.
你到底在说什么
What are you talking about?
这里很安全
It's safe.
这里有食物 有住处
There is food, there is shelter.
还有很多活人 看在上帝的份上
There's people, for God's sake.
这只是他们给你看的表象
That's what they show you.
除非他们赶你走 你就无法自由离开
But you can't leave unless they make you.
你真是大脑进水了
You are not making any sense.
米琼恩 你需要休息一会
Mich, maybe you need to sit for a minute.
你必须要相信我
You need to trust me.
那你必须给我个更好的理由
Mich, maybe you need to give me more to go on.
这里有我们想要的一切
We got a good thing going here.
我以为我们只是暂避
I thought this was temporary.
我觉得应该长住
And I think we need this.
我们要想办法适应这里
I want to give this place a real shot.
我努力过了
I tried.
闯进别人的家也能算努力吗
Breaking into houses? That is not trying.
这是蓄意捣乱
That is sabotaging.
这地方根本不像他们所说的那样
This place is not what they say it is.
瑞克
Rick?
大家都很担心你
Everybody's worried about you.
你该离开这里
You shouldn't be in here.
出去吧
Come on out.
瑞克
Rick.
你不必自己承担这一切
You don't have to do this all by yourself.
好吗
Okay?
我们的牢区已经清理干净了
Our cell block is cleared.
我们只需要把所有的门都再关上
We'll just close off all the doors again.
瑞克 跟我离开这里
Rick we want you just come on with me.
好吗
Okay?
瑞克
Rick.
好吧 好吧
Yeah… yeah…
是我
It's me.
好极了
Hey, all right.
又逮到行尸了
We got us a bite.
有不少啊 把它们拉起来
Yeah, we got us some. Let's hook them up.
就这样
That's it.
看看我们抓到了什么
Ho, whoa! Look what we got here.
来啊 咬我啊
Oh, yeah. Come get it.
来咬啊 真厉害
Come get it. Whoa! Jeez!
看这只 这只还太小
Look at this one. It's too little.
- 得杀了这只 - 等一下
- We're gonna have to kill it. - Hold on.
它眼睛好像不太对劲
There is something interesing in its eyes.
那不杀它吗
So don't kill it?
杀不杀都行
It's a maybe for me.
给
Here you go.
你也动一次手
Get your hands dirty for once, huh?
来吧下来
All right. Come on. Come on down.
把它们弄下来
Let them down now.
上吧 小米
Come on, Milty.
干掉它 小子 干掉它
Get her, boy! Get her!
看哪
Oh, yeah!
看到没有
Oh! Oh, man! I tell you what,
你那外套还真不赖
I take back anything I said about that jacket.
来这儿 对着我
Come here. Let me see her.
对着我
Let me see her.
莫尔 看这个
Merle, check this one out.
它快和你一样丑了
He's almost as ugly as you.
我勒个去
Holy shit!
是啊 它是个坏脾气 对吧
Yeah! He's a mean one, huh?
看它啊
Look at him.
好 现在把它弄倒 来吧 弄倒它
Yeah, now get him down now. Come on, get him down.
把它弄倒 你好哦
Get him down. Yeow!
放松 张嘴 宝贝
Easy now. Open up, baby.
咬到了 好嘞
Got him! Yeah!
就这样 来吧
There we go. Come on.
别跟我胡来 宝贝
Don't give me no shit, boy.
就这样
There.
行尸离得不远
Company's close.
跟紧
Stay tight.
（索菲）
晚餐有了
Hello, dinner.
我可不把那个放我包里
I'm not putting that in my bag.
（婴儿奶粉）
喂 喂 姑娘们
Hey, hey, hey, girls!
你们匆匆忙忙的这是去哪儿
Where y'all off to in such a hurry?
喂 等等
Hey, come on, now. Come on. Hey, hey, hey.
你俩就这么离开 多伤我心啊
Y'all are breaking my heart running away like that.
我们要走了
We're leaving.
快到宵禁了
It's almost curfew.
我得派个人护送
I'd have to arrange an escort.
我是说 派对还没完呢
I mean, the party's still going on.
好吧
Alright.
在此稍等
Wait here a second.
布朗尼 过来
Brownie! Come here.
听着 兄弟
Listen up, bro.
总督曾跟我们说过
The Governor told us we were free.
我们随时都来去自由
to come and go whenever we liked.
亲爱的 这不是针对谁
Sweetheart, nothing personal here,
可是你得退后
but you're gonna have to step back.
看到没
See?
他们总是用各种借口留下我们
There's always a reason why we can't leave yet.
安全
Clear!
我要是你们 我会在天黑前找个藏身处
Now if I was y'all, I'd find some shelter before nightfall.
他们知道我们要走 这都是在演戏
They knew we were coming. This was all for show.
你越说越夸张了 这只是你的猜测
Do you hear yourself? How can you know that?
他们有何必要这么做
And why would they bother?
姑娘们
Ladies?
- 把门关上 - 不行
- Close the gates. - No!
我可是求着总督把你留下的
I practically begged the Governor to let you stay.
- 我可没这要求 - 你不需要
- I didn't ask for that. - You didn't have to.
朋友间要互相帮助
That's what friends do for each other.
我就是在帮你
It goes both ways.
那你是想在外面用铁链拴着行尸
So you want to run around out there.
靠吃树枝到处逃亡吗
with walkers on chains eating twigs?
- 我是说 那样就好吗 - 我们能靠自己
- I mean, is… is that right? - We held our own.
八个月 八个月来我们在路上四处奔波
Eight months! Eight months on the road moving place to place,
靠拾荒糊口 以冷藏室为家
scavenging, living in a meat locker.
那不是生活
That was no life.
我累了 我很累了
I'm tired. I'm tired.
我可没法像那样再活八个月
I don't have another eight months in me. Not like that.
可是你 我
And you, I…
我怎样
What about me?
我怕你会从此消失
I'm afriaid you are gonna disappear.
我们之前总是说这样的地方 不是吗
We always talked about this place, didn't we?
一个避难所
A refuge.
那种念头支撑着我们一路前行
That idea is what kept us going.
你是走还是不走
Are you coming or not?
不要这样做
Don't do this.
别给我下最后通牒
Don't give me an ultimatum.
我们一起经历了那么多
Not after everything.
你到底是走 还是不走
Are you coming or not?
反正你也是拖我后腿的
You'd just slow me down anyway.
米琼恩
Michonne!
很遗憾你朋友还是走了
I'm sorry things didn't work out with your friend.
别人主动离开你 这感觉很怪
Weird to lose someone by their own choice.
我以为那样的日子已经过去了呢
Thought those days had gone.
不确定这是否会让你感觉好些
Not sure this will make you feel better,
但是我肯定你应该喝一杯
but I'm sure you could use a drink.
让人陪陪
Some company.
做点别的事 别去想它
Something to take your mind off of it for a bit.
来吧
Come on.
伙计们 他们回来了
Guys, they are back!
来啊 来啊 来啊
Come on! Come on! Come on!
你们想吃东西吗 来啊
You want something to eat? Come on!
来啊
Come on!
贝丝
Beth.
她怎么样
How's she doing?
对不起
I'm sorry.
喝吧 喝吧
Come on. Come on.
给她取名字了吗
She got a name yet?
还没有
Not yet.
但我想可以叫她索菲亚
But I was thinking maybe Sophia.
或者卡萝尔
Then there's Carol, too.
或者
And…
安德莉亚
Andrea.
艾米
Amy.
杰奎
Jacqui.
帕特里夏
Patricia.
或者洛莉 我也不知道
Or… Lori. I don't know.
喜欢喝吗
You like that?
小拽女
Little ass-kicker.
是吧 这个名字不错 是吧
Right? That's a good name, right?
小拽女 你也喜欢 是吧
Little ass-kicker. You like that, huh?
你喜欢吗 小甜心
You like that, sweetheart?
还我妻子
Give… my… wife…
你好吗 上来
How are you? Come on up here.
快来 这边
Come on, this way.
我有全场最棒座位
I got the best seats in the house.
你好吗
Hey, how you doing?
开心点嘛 真是的
Get a barrel. Come on.
- 够吵的啊 - 是啊
- It's a little loud. - Yeah.
- 加油啊 - 我感觉不太…
- Come on! - I don't feel…
加油啊
Come on!
莫尔
Merle! Merle! Merle!
我一只手就能把他摆平
I'm gonna kick his ass one-handed.
见鬼去吧 我不用手也能摆平
The hell with it. No-handed!
不用手
No hands!
好啦 好戏开始啦
All right, let's get it on!
来啊
Yeah! Come on!
来啊 起来 起来
Come on, get up. Get up.
他就会那么点儿功夫 乡亲们
He's got nothing. Nothing, folks.
- 起来 - 来啊
- Get up. - Come on!
来吧
Come on!
别啊 让他们继续打
Come on, let 'em fight.
来吧小子 我们好好玩玩
Come on, pretty boy. Let's dance.
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
这是什么鬼东西
What the hell is this?
发泄消遣嘛
It's a way to blow off steam.
消遣
Blow off steam?
慢跑才叫消遣
You go for a jog to blow off steam.
这… 这叫变态
This is… this is sick.
看看周围 大家都很开心
Look around. Everyone's having a great time.
野蛮人才喜欢这东西
It's barbaric.
这是事先编排好的
It's staged.
没错 我们拔掉了行尸的牙
Yeah, we pull out the biter's teeth.
不过是场表演
It's just all for show.
太疯狂了
It's just That's crazy.
你就因为这才留下行尸吗
This is your reason for keeping walkers around?
人们需要娱乐
People need entertainment.
所以你就建了个角斗场吗
So your solution is gladiator fights?
它们被削弱了 它们在我们控制中
We're reducing these things. We're controlling them.
我们驱除了人们心中的恐惧
We're shining a light on the monster under the bed.
很有趣的
It's fun.
看完表演大家会更舒服
It makes people feel better about the whole thing.
这简直是个灾难
It's a slippery slope.
你是在教大家行尸并不危险
You're teaching them that walkers aren't dangerous.
我们是在教大家不用害怕
We're teaching them not to be afraid.
来啊小样
Come on, baby.
来啊 不就点小伤嘛
Come on. Walk it off, huh?
一
Uno!
二
Dos!
- 三 - 好样的
- Tres! - Well done!
喂
Hello?